<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Moon Syntax - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[The decentralized { organization } that’s shaking up the world of blockchain { startups }. With a focus on { developing }, { managing }, and { funding } cutting-edge projects, our team of { experts } delivers unparalleled support and guidance. moonsyntax.com - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>Moon Syntax - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 11:01:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/moonsyntax" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitcoin Halving: Half the Rewards, Double the Excitement!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/bitcoin-halving-half-the-rewards-double-the-excitement-04cc75c5cbfd?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/04cc75c5cbfd</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 09:11:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-11-26T09:09:53.431Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*k4d1qlr0sx74yT7-iu7wqg.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction:</h3><p>The world of cryptocurrency is abuzz with anticipation as we approach the next Bitcoin halving scheduled for 2024. These halving events, occurring approximately every four years, have proven to be pivotal moments in Bitcoin’s history, reshaping its trajectory and influencing market dynamics.</p><h3>Understanding Bitcoin Halvings:</h3><p>Bitcoin halvings, occurring in 2012, 2016, 2020, and now slated for 2024, are events that cut the rate at which new Bitcoin is created through mining, resulting in a reduction in the asset’s issuance. This phenomenon, referred to as a supply shock, has historically played a significant role in driving the price of Bitcoin to all-time highs in the years following the halving.</p><h3>Historical Trends:</h3><p>Examining the historical data reveals a compelling pattern of significant surges in the wake of each of the last four Bitcoin halvings. The first halving occurred in November 2012 and marked the beginning of a remarkable trend that unfolded in subsequent years.</p><ol><li><strong>2012 Halving:</strong> In the aftermath of the first halving, Bitcoin witnessed an extraordinary surge, reaching an all-time high in 2013. The price surged by an astonishing percentage, with a notable increase of 8450% from its pre-halving value.</li><li><strong>2016 Halving:</strong> Following the second halving in July 2016, the cryptocurrency market experienced another substantial surge. Bitcoin reached unprecedented highs in 2017, with the price surging by 290% from its pre-halving level.</li><li><strong>2020 Halving: </strong>The third halving, which took place in May 2020, continued the historical trend. Bitcoin’s value skyrocketed, hitting a new all-time high in 2021. The surge post-2020 halving amounted 260%, further reinforcing the correlation between halving events and price escalation.</li></ol><h3>Post-Halving Reality:</h3><p>Contrary to popular expectations, the immediate aftermath of a Bitcoin halving does not witness an overnight doubling of prices. Instead, it is characterized by a period of consolidation and adjustments. This phase is crucial for the market to absorb the impact of the reduced issuance and for new price trends to emerge.</p><h3>Limited Supply and Issuance Mechanism:</h3><p>A key feature that sets Bitcoin apart is its limited supply of 21 million coins. With over 19 million already mined, the fourth halving will see 96.875% of all Bitcoin in existence. The miner’s block reward will be halved to 3.125 BTC per new block, aligning with the protocol’s gradual reduction in new coin issuance.</p><h3>Conclusion:</h3><p>As we approach the 2024 Bitcoin halving, the crypto community awaits the outcome with bated breath. Historical trends suggest that big price fluctuations may occur in the aftermath, but the market’s reaction is intrinsically unpredictable. Whether Bitcoin soars to new heights or endures brief swings, the core concepts of limited supply and supply halving are critical to understanding the dynamics of the world’s top cryptocurrency. Investors and enthusiasts must approach the post-halving phase with an eye on market trends and a complete awareness of the elements impacting Bitcoin’s future voyage.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=04cc75c5cbfd" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/bitcoin-halving-half-the-rewards-double-the-excitement-04cc75c5cbfd">Bitcoin Halving: Half the Rewards, Double the Excitement!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoinGecko’s Dance with Crypto: Are They Playing a Risky Game?]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/coingeckos-dance-with-crypto-are-they-playing-a-risky-game-56a621879a9e?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/56a621879a9e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[investing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[listings]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 04:23:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-11-25T04:22:54.933Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ce8wLxs-GNyajScbrOA0ig.png" /></figure><h4>Introduction:</h4><p>In the ever-expanding universe of cryptocurrencies, where innovation and chaos coexist, platforms like CoinGecko play a pivotal role in guiding investors through the labyrinth of digital assets. However, as the crypto market witnesses an unprecedented surge in the number of projects, questions are arising about the integrity of platforms like CoinGecko, especially when it comes to listing seemingly questionable projects. Are they, intentionally or unintentionally, contributing to the proliferation of meme coins and low-tech projects that plague the crypto space?</p><h4>The Numbers Game:</h4><p>Let’s start with the numbers. CoinGecko currently boasts a staggering 11,000 listed coins, outnumbering its closest rival, CoinMarketCap, by 3,000. To put this into perspective, in 2017, the total number of altcoins stood at 5,000, with Bitcoin dominance at 53%. Fast forward to today, and despite a mind-boggling 26,000+ altcoins, Bitcoin dominance remains unchanged at 53%.</p><h4>The Crypto Explosion:</h4><p>The past few year has been labeled a “Cambrian explosion” of crypto assets, with nearly 18,000 created between 2014 and 2023. This surge, however, comes with its own set of challenges. A considerable number of these assets are now dead.</p><h4>CoinGecko’s Role:</h4><p>CoinGecko, a prominent player in the crypto data space, claims to evaluate projects holistically before listing. However, the exact criteria remain undisclosed, leaving users in the dark about the standards a project must meet for inclusion. In recent reports shared by coingecko — out of the 6,300 cryptocurrencies they listed in 2022, 1,866 have already died.</p><h4>Questioning the Listing Process:</h4><p>The alarming rate at which projects are meeting their demise raises a critical question: <strong>Is the listing process flawed?</strong> If CoinGecko is contributing to the listing of projects that are destined for failure, it calls into question the efficacy of their evaluation criteria. Investors deserve transparency about why a project is listed, and if it later becomes defunct, what went wrong.</p><p>Moreover, there’s a lingering question about financial transactions — is CoinGecko accepting money from these projects, or is there a possibility of them being unwittingly involved in potential scams? Shedding light on these aspects is essential for the community’s trust and understanding. If the projects are faltering post-listing, users need a comprehensive explanation to discern whether there are shortcomings in the evaluation process or if financial transactions are muddying the waters of trust.</p><h4>A Plethora of Dead Coins:</h4><p>With so many projects meeting their demise, it’s evident that hype alone can’t sustain the market. The community needs assurance that projects listed on platforms like CoinGecko are not just part of a short-lived trend but have a solid foundation and purpose.<strong> </strong>The onus is on CoinGecko to refine its listing process, ensuring that only robust and promising projects make the cut.</p><h4>Conclusion:</h4><p>As the crypto market continues to evolve, platforms like CoinGecko wield considerable influence over investor sentiment. The proliferation of meme coins and the demise of numerous projects suggest that the ecosystem is at a crossroads. CoinGecko must reassess its listing criteria, prioritize transparency, and actively contribute to the cultivation of a crypto landscape dominated by innovation rather than speculation. Investors deserve more than a gamble; they deserve a trustworthy guide through the ever-expanding crypto cosmos.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=56a621879a9e" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/coingeckos-dance-with-crypto-are-they-playing-a-risky-game-56a621879a9e">CoinGecko’s Dance with Crypto: Are They Playing a Risky Game?</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dangers of Mixing Bitcoins : A Closer Look at Privacy Risks]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/the-dangers-of-mixing-bitcoins-a-closer-look-at-privacy-risks-0ec22daacd91?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/0ec22daacd91</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 14:44:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-11-24T14:44:45.731Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>The Dangers of Mixing Bitcoins : A Closer Look at Privacy Risks</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZghDRkxp2XzK8GHq_rdFvw.png" /></figure><p>In the ever-expanding realm of cryptocurrencies, the pursuit of privacy has birthed practices like bitcoin mixing, a process where coins are blended to obscure their origin. While the desire to safeguard personal information is commendable, diving into the world of bitcoin mixing exposes users to significant risks and potential legal consequences.</p><h3>Unveiling Bitcoin Mixing</h3><p>Bitcoin mixing, also known as coin mixing or tumbling, is the practice of merging one’s cryptocurrency funds with those of others, effectively severing the traceable link between the sender and receiver. This process provides a semblance of anonymity, as it becomes challenging to trace the origins of the mixed coins.</p><h3>The Illusion of Anonymity</h3><p>While the promise of enhanced privacy may be enticing, the use of bitcoin mixers carries inherent dangers. By mingling funds with those potentially connected to serious crimes, users inadvertently place themselves at legal and ethical crossroads.</p><p>Consider this scenario, mixed coins intertwined with those originating from dark web drug markets or other illicit sources. The very attempt to shield one’s identity could, ironically, lead to entanglement in more significant legal issues. The allure of enhanced privacy must be carefully weighed against the potential perils that lurk beneath the surface.</p><h3>Legal and Ethical Jeopardy</h3><p>The inherent risks of bitcoin mixing extend beyond the mere possibility of connecting with criminal funds. Law enforcement agencies globally are increasingly scrutinizing cryptocurrency transactions. In fact, according to a report by Chainalysis, a leading blockchain analysis firm, in 2022, illicit activities constituted only 0.34% of all cryptocurrency transactions, yet they accounted for 17.4% of the total transaction volume. This underscores the high concentration of illicit funds within a small fraction of transactions.</p><h3>The Need for Caution</h3><p>In our perspective, exercising caution when considering bitcoin mixers is imperative. While privacy is undoubtedly a crucial aspect of financial transactions, the risk of inadvertently aligning with criminal funds far outweighs the benefits. It is essential to navigate the cryptocurrency landscape with a clear understanding of the legal and ethical ramifications associated with such practices.</p><h3>Striking the Right Balance</h3><p>In conclusion, while bitcoin mixing may promise enhanced privacy, its associated hazards are undeniable. Striking the right balance between safeguarding one’s privacy and avoiding inadvertent connections with criminal activities remains a formidable challenge. Before embracing bitcoin mixing, users should meticulously consider the potential consequences and stay informed about the evolving legal landscape surrounding cryptocurrency transactions.</p><p>As the cryptocurrency space continues to evolve, staying informed and making decisions with a clear understanding of the risks involved is paramount. Privacy matters, but it must be pursued with due diligence to ensure that the pursuit of anonymity does not inadvertently lead down a path of legal and ethical dilemmas.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=0ec22daacd91" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/the-dangers-of-mixing-bitcoins-a-closer-look-at-privacy-risks-0ec22daacd91">The Dangers of Mixing Bitcoins : A Closer Look at Privacy Risks</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Counting Down to Crypto’s Big Event: The Bitcoin Halving in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/counting-down-to-cryptos-big-event-the-bitcoin-halving-in-2024-9062bdbe623a?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9062bdbe623a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin-halving]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 06:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-11-24T06:48:58.620Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*hXR-f6dYdSZdMTDjKuBjNw.png" /></figure><p>The crypto world is abuzz with anticipation as we approach a significant event in the Bitcoin community — the much-anticipated Bitcoin halving. Scheduled for April 2024, this event occurs approximately every four years, reshaping the dynamics of the cryptocurrency market. As the countdown to the Bitcoin halving begins, the crypto community, including influential figures like Chang Peng Zhao, CEO of Binance, is gearing up for a transformative period.</p><h4>Understanding Bitcoin Halving:</h4><p>Bitcoin halving is a crucial event in the life of the leading cryptocurrency. It involves a deliberate reduction in the reward given to Bitcoin miners for validating transactions and securing the network. The current reward of 6.25 BTC per block will be halved to 3.125 BTC during the upcoming event. This scarcity mechanism is built into the Bitcoin protocol, ensuring a finite supply and creating a sense of rarity akin to precious metals like gold.</p><h4>The Countdown Begins:</h4><p>Chang Peng Zhao, known for his role at the helm of Binance, recently took to Twitter to set the countdown for the next Bitcoin halving. In a post on the X platform (formerly Twitter), he emphasized that the clock is ticking, with only 135 days remaining until the much-anticipated event. This move by Zhao serves as a symbolic gesture, reminding the crypto community of the imminent change in the Bitcoin landscape.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Ka53CTtNMYeZTVx_UTay0Q.png" /></figure><h4>Implications for the Crypto Community:</h4><p>The countdown to the Bitcoin halving marks a period of heightened interest and speculation within the crypto community. Previous halving events have been associated with significant price movements and market dynamics. For instance, during the last bull cycle that commenced in 2020, the price of Bitcoin traded below $10,000 just two months before the halving. Subsequently, the market witnessed a surge, and Bitcoin’s value soared, capturing the attention of investors and enthusiasts alike.</p><h4>Why It Matters:</h4><p>The Bitcoin halving is more than just a scheduled technical adjustment; it’s a fundamental aspect of Bitcoin’s monetary policy. The reduced mining rewards serve to control inflation, maintain scarcity, and uphold the decentralized nature of the cryptocurrency. As the countdown continues, the crypto community is closely watching for potential impacts on market dynamics, mining operations, and, most importantly, the price of Bitcoin.</p><h4>Preparing for the Future:</h4><p>As the countdown to the Bitcoin halving progresses, market participants are strategizing and adjusting their positions. Traders, investors, and miners alike are closely analyzing historical trends and speculating on potential outcomes. The upcoming halving event is poised to be a defining moment for the crypto space, offering both challenges and opportunities.</p><h4>Conclusion:</h4><p>In the world of cryptocurrency, few events generate as much excitement and speculation as the Bitcoin halving. Stay tuned as the countdown clock ticks away, bringing us closer to a new chapter in the fascinating journey of Bitcoin and the broader world of cryptocurrencies.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9062bdbe623a" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/counting-down-to-cryptos-big-event-the-bitcoin-halving-in-2024-9062bdbe623a">Counting Down to Crypto’s Big Event: The Bitcoin Halving in 2024</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Binance CEO Pleaded Guilty Admits To Pay $4.3 Billion Fine]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/binance-ceo-pleaded-guilty-admits-to-pay-4-3-billion-fine-d88ae4eec264?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/d88ae4eec264</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:40:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-11-23T17:40:21.265Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Qd7Myb5yQMPf4TVhNUccDQ.png" /></figure><p>In a startling revelation, Changpeng Zhao, the founder of Binance, the world’s leading cryptocurrency exchange, has admitted to fraud and stepped down from his position as Chief Executive Officer. This bombshell announcement comes amidst a backdrop of regulatory scrutiny, resulting in Binance agreeing to pay a staggering $4.3 billion in fines for money-laundering violations.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*urHDW2vmDLbe8wlY_dfOig.png" /></figure><h3>Binance Faces Record Fine:</h3><p>This unprecedented move follows the recent FTX debacle, underscoring the increasing regulatory pressure on the cryptocurrency industry. Binance, a behemoth in the crypto space, pleaded guilty to violating US anti-money-laundering laws, leading to the hefty fine. The settlement allows Binance to continue its operations, assuring users, including those in the crucial US market, that services will persist despite the leadership change.</p><h3>Bitcoin’s Resilience:</h3><p>Despite the chaos surrounding Binance, Bitcoin demonstrated remarkable stability. The BTC/USD pair held its ground near $37,000, showing resilience against the potential market turbulence. After a brief dip to $35,500, Bitcoin rebounded, signaling confidence among investors even in the face of a major industry shakeup.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/700/0*hrO6vITdrfOIvVpL.png" /></figure><h3>Zhao’s Admission and Forbes Feature:</h3><p>In a contrite message on the platform X, Zhao openly admitted to making mistakes. This admission adds a layer of transparency to the situation, drawing parallels with other high-profile figures facing legal issues. Notably, Forbes has featured Zhao alongside individuals like Sam Bankman-Fried, dubbed the “next Warren Buffett,” and Elizabeth Holmes, the purported “next Steve Jobs,” further amplifying the gravity of the situation.</p><h3>The Future of Bitcoin:</h3><p>Amidst this upheaval, the future of Bitcoin remains a topic of intense speculation. Analysts and enthusiasts are closely monitoring the market to gauge the long-term impact of Binance’s legal troubles on the broader cryptocurrency ecosystem.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=d88ae4eec264" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/binance-ceo-pleaded-guilty-admits-to-pay-4-3-billion-fine-d88ae4eec264">Binance CEO Pleaded Guilty Admits To Pay $4.3 Billion Fine</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crypto User Accidentally Pays a Whopping 60 BTC in Transaction Fee Due to Typo!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/crypto-user-accidentally-pays-a-whopping-60-btc-in-transaction-fee-due-to-typo-083dfc3e5d5c?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/083dfc3e5d5c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[transactions]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 13:12:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-11-23T13:12:01.670Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*A_pGkE7wmjllm_rNuuM_2A.png" /></figure><blockquote><em>A Costly Mistake Sends Shockwaves Through the Crypto Community.</em></blockquote><p>In a jaw-dropping incident that has left the crypto space buzzing with disbelief, an unfortunate user recently committed a costly error while conducting a transaction, resulting in a staggering fee payment of 60 BTC (approximately $3,130,787.50 USD)! The blunder occurred during what should have been a routine crypto transaction, but a simple typo in the fee input turned it into an eye-watering financial mishap.</p><h3>Transaction Details:</h3><p>The incident unfolded on the Bitcoin blockchain, with the transaction in question identified as <a href="https://blockchair.com/bitcoin/transaction/b5a2af5845a8d3796308ff9840e567b14cf6bb158ff26c999e6f9a1f5448f9aa">b5a2af5845a8d3796308ff9840e567b14cf6bb158ff26c999e6f9a1f5448f9aa</a>. The user intended to transfer 55.76998378 BTC (equivalent to $2,087,191.60 USD), but due to a typo in the fee field, a staggering 83.65497568 BTC (approximately $3,130,787.50 USD) was inadvertently set as the transaction fee.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/688/0*Onaocre8ZNXlkpXN.jpeg" /></figure><h3>How the Typo Unfolded:</h3><p>Upon closer inspection, it was revealed that the fee per vbyte was an astonishing 76,397,240 satoshi, a figure that stands out as an anomaly in regular crypto transactions. Sources indicate that a simple typographical error led to the unintentional overpayment, highlighting the need for users to exercise caution and double-check transaction details before finalizing transfers.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/327/0*VK-RGixHDWJNxDhl.png" /></figure><h3>Blockchain Community Reacts:</h3><p>As news of this costly mishap spread across the blockchain community, reactions ranged from sympathy to shock. Crypto enthusiasts and experts took to various forums and social media platforms to discuss the incident, emphasizing the importance of user vigilance to prevent such costly mistakes in the future.</p><h3>Learning from the Incident:</h3><p>While this incident serves as a cautionary tale for the crypto community, it also underscores the need for user-friendly interfaces that can minimize the risk of human error in transactions. Industry experts are now calling for enhanced safety measures and additional confirmation prompts to prevent similar incidents from occurring in the future.</p><h3>Conclusion:</h3><p>The crypto space, known for its innovation and occasional surprises, now witnesses an unfortunate episode where a simple mistake cost a user dearly. As the blockchain community reflects on this incident, it serves as a reminder to exercise caution, double-check details, and advocate for improvements in user interface design to prevent such costly errors in the evolving world of digital transactions.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=083dfc3e5d5c" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/crypto-user-accidentally-pays-a-whopping-60-btc-in-transaction-fee-due-to-typo-083dfc3e5d5c">Crypto User Accidentally Pays a Whopping 60 BTC in Transaction Fee Due to Typo!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recovered 2.1 BTC from a Damaged Device]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/recovered-2-1-btc-from-a-damaged-device-ba145e5f3fe9?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ba145e5f3fe9</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[recovery]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin-recovery]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 22:50:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-09-29T22:50:47.931Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*WP18v7ohzluqY01_JoPqhQ.png" /></figure><p>Our team of experts at <a href="https://moonsyntax.com/">Moon Syntax</a> recently recovered 2.1 BTC (Bitcoin) from a severely damaged OnePlus 7T device. This shows our commitment to excellence and our proficiency in cryptocurrency recovery services.</p><h3>Challenge</h3><p>Our client was a user of the Samurai wallet on Android, known for its security and privacy features. However, even the most secure wallet couldn’t prevent a devastating hardware failure. The client’s Android device suffered a complete breakdown, rendering both the display and the motherboard unusable. He remembered 12 out of the 13 words of their wallet passphrase, with the elusive 13th word being the “BIP passphrase.”</p><p>Upon realizing the severity of the situation, our client attempted to recover their funds using various alternative wallets, including Ledger and Electrum wallet, using the 12 words. Unfortunately, these attempts were in vain as the missing 13th word was crucial for accessing the funds.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*J-nh_uGLRwL_aQnAsDg1Wg.png" /></figure><h3>Assessment</h3><p>When the client approached us for assistance, they couldn’t provide a definitive answer regarding the length of the 13th word. Uncertainty surrounded whether it exceeded 12 letters or not. This posed a significant challenge to our recovery efforts. To address this ambiguity, we devised a two-pronged strategy.</p><h3>Our Two-Pronged Approach:</h3><h4><strong>Recover the Phone and Access the Wallet:</strong></h4><p>Our first option was to recover the damaged Android device. This was a complex and time-consuming process that required technical expertise and the right equipment. We understood that this approach had its own set of challenges, but it was essential to explore every possibility to retrieve the lost funds.</p><h4>Brute Force the 13th Word:</h4><p>Recognizing that the recovery of the device might not be guaranteed, we simultaneously initiated a plan to brute force the missing 13th word. We prepared for an extensive and exhaustive process that involved attempting every possible combination of dictionary words and symbols until the correct word was found. This was no small task, and we knew it would require a dedicated system and considerable time.</p><h3>Result</h3><p>In a fortunate turn of events, our efforts paid off. The damaged Android device was successfully recovered, and we gained access to the Samurai wallet. Our client’s funds were once again within reach. The successful recovery of the lost cryptocurrency was a testament to our team’s dedication, technical expertise, and innovative approach.</p><blockquote><a href="https://blog.moonsyntax.com/posts/recovered-21-btc-from-a-damaged-device/">Read this Article on our website</a></blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ba145e5f3fe9" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/recovered-2-1-btc-from-a-damaged-device-ba145e5f3fe9">Recovered 2.1 BTC from a Damaged Device</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lessons from the Terra Luna Crash]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/lessons-from-the-terra-luna-crash-8f97df35ec7b?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/8f97df35ec7b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[terra]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[market]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:14:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-09-29T20:54:24.805Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*l2vlfJONsGRQHRr9G1AW5Q.jpeg" /></figure><p>The recent crash of Terra Luna (LUNA) and its stablecoin, Terra USD (UST), has sent shockwaves throughout the cryptocurrency world. Many investors find themselves grappling with significant losses. However, in the midst of this unfortunate event, there are crucial lessons to be learned. In this blog post, we’ll delve deeper into these lessons to help you navigate the volatile cryptocurrency market more effectively.</p><h4>1. Due Diligence Matters</h4><p>The importance of proper due diligence cannot be overstated. In the world of cryptocurrency, where projects can emerge rapidly and fade just as quickly, taking the time to research and understand the intricacies of a project is paramount. Beyond checking the project’s whitepaper and website, delve into the backgrounds of the team members. Look for their previous experiences and successes in the blockchain and tech industry. Evaluate the project’s technological innovations and its potential to address real-world problems. By conducting thorough due diligence, you’ll be better equipped to make informed investment decisions.</p><h4>2. Implementing Risk Management</h4><p>In the aftermath of the Terra Luna crash, many investors were left wondering how they could have protected themselves. The answer lies in implementing a robust risk management strategy. Begin by defining your risk tolerance. Understand how much of your portfolio you are willing to allocate to high-risk assets like cryptocurrencies. Setting stop-loss orders is another essential tool in your risk management arsenal. These orders automatically sell a portion of your assets if their value falls to a predetermined level, helping you limit potential losses. Furthermore, consider diversifying your investments to spread risk across different asset classes and projects.</p><h4>3. Avoiding Red Flags</h4><p>The Terra Luna crash was not only a financial shock but also a reminder of the significance of red flags in the cryptocurrency space. Public behavior, particularly on social media, can provide valuable insights into the professionalism and trustworthiness of project founders. Founders who engage in unprofessional conduct or public disputes may not be reliable stewards of your investments. Prioritize projects led by teams that exhibit transparency, professionalism, and a commitment to their community. Their track record and reputation are powerful indicators of project reliability.</p><h4>4. Diversification Is Key</h4><p>While cryptocurrencies and decentralized finance offer exciting opportunities for high returns, they are not without risk. To safeguard your financial stability, diversify your portfolio. This means spreading your investments across various asset classes, such as stocks, bonds, real estate, and cryptocurrencies. By doing so, you reduce the impact of a single asset’s downturn on your overall wealth. Additionally, consider keeping a portion of your assets in a licensed financial institution for emergencies. This “safety net” can provide peace of mind during times of market turbulence.</p><h4>5. Prepare for Black Swan Events</h4><p>The Terra Luna crash is a classic example of a black swan event — an unforeseen, extreme occurrence with profound consequences. Cryptocurrency markets can be particularly susceptible to these events due to their inherent volatility and susceptibility to external factors. To prepare for such events, stay informed about the broader financial and geopolitical landscape. Regularly monitor news and events that could potentially impact the cryptocurrency market. Being proactive and adaptable in your investment strategy can help you respond effectively when the unexpected occurs.</p><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>The Terra Luna crash serves as a stark reminder of the need for vigilance and informed decision-making in the cryptocurrency market. By conducting comprehensive due diligence, avoiding red flags, implementing robust risk management strategies, diversifying your portfolio, and staying alert to black swan events, you can navigate the cryptocurrency market more confidently and minimize the risk of significant losses. While cryptocurrencies offer exciting investment opportunities, they should be approached with caution, with a focus on prudent risk management and long-term financial stability.</p><blockquote><a href="https://blog.moonsyntax.com/posts/lessons-from-the-terra-luna-crash/">Read this Article on our website.</a></blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=8f97df35ec7b" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/lessons-from-the-terra-luna-crash-8f97df35ec7b">Lessons from the Terra Luna Crash</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proton Browser — A Privacy-Focused Alternative to Brave?]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/proton-browser-a-privacy-focused-alternative-to-brave-5d3cf1d63e53?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/5d3cf1d63e53</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[proton]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[browsers]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:11:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-09-29T20:57:34.796Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Proton Browser — A Privacy-Focused Alternative to Brave?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*XRU2jRpm3-FEdMZ-bOGdqw.jpeg" /></figure><p>In today’s digital age, online privacy has become a rare commodity. With data breaches and cyber attacks becoming increasingly common, it’s no surprise that people are looking for ways to protect themselves. <a href="https://protonmail.com/">ProtonMail</a>, a popular email service known for its strong focus on security and privacy, may have the answer. We at Moonsyntax believe that ProtonBrowser, a hypothetical privacy-focused browser, is not only a great idea but also a likely reality in the near future. In this blog post, we’ll explore why.</p><h3>The Need for a Privacy-Focused Browser:</h3><p>Privacy-conscious individuals have long been concerned about the amount of data that browsers collect and share with third parties. Google Chrome, for example, has been criticized for its permissive data collection policies, which allow the company to gather extensive information about its users’ browsing habits. This data can then be used to create highly targeted advertisements, which often feel intrusive and invasive.</p><p>Moreover, many browsers fail to adequately protect users from tracking cookies, which can follow them across different websites and devices. This lack of protection allows companies to build detailed profiles of users’ interests, behavior, and demographic information. It’s clear that a browser that prioritizes user privacy is desperately needed.</p><h3>Why ProtonBrowser Makes Sense:</h3><p>Enter ProtonBrowser, a hypothetical browser that builds upon ProtonMail’s commitment to security and privacy. Here are some compelling reasons why we believe ProtonBrowser is a natural extension of ProtonMail’s services:</p><h4>Aligned Business Model:</h4><p>ProtonMail’s business model revolves around offering premium features to paying customers, rather than relying on advertising revenue. This aligns perfectly with a privacy-focused browser, as it eliminates the need for intrusive data collection and ad targeting.</p><h4>Existing Security Infrastructure:</h4><p>ProtonMail already has a robust security infrastructure in place, including end-to-end encryption and zero-access encryption. Extending this infrastructure to a browser would provide users with unparalleled security and peace of mind.</p><h4>Dedicated User Base:</h4><p>ProtonMail boasts a large and dedicated user base, comprised of individuals who value their online privacy. It’s reasonable to assume that many of these users would eagerly adopt a privacy-focused browser offered by the same company.</p><h4>Competitive Advantage:</h4><p>By offering a privacy-focused browser, ProtonMail could differentiate itself from other email providers and attract new users who prioritize online privacy.</p><h3>Features We Expect from ProtonBrowser:</h3><p>While ProtonBrowser is still a hypothetical product, we can imagine several features that would make it stand out:</p><ol><li><strong>End-to-End Encryption:</strong> All web traffic should be encrypted, ensuring that sensitive data remains protected from prying eyes.</li><li><strong>No Tracking: </strong>ProtonBrowser should block tracking cookies and ads, preventing companies from monitoring users’ browsing activities.</li><li><strong>Anonymization:</strong> Users should have the option to browse the internet anonymously, using temporary IP addresses and other techniques to conceal their identity.</li><li><strong>Built-in VPN: </strong>A built-in VPN would enable users to route their internet traffic through secure servers, shielding their data from hackers and snooping organizations.</li><li><strong>Advanced Password Management:</strong> ProtonBrowser could integrate a password manager that generates and stores unique, complex passwords, making it easier for users to practice good password hygiene.</li></ol><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>A privacy-focused browser like ProtonBrowser is not only a great idea but also a logical next step for ProtonMail. Given the company’s dedication to security and user privacy, we at Moonsyntax predict that ProtonBrowser will soon become a reality. Such a browser would offer a unique value proposition, setting it apart from competitors and solidifying ProtonMail’s position as a leader in the privacy space. When it comes to online privacy, we believe that the future belongs to those who innovate and prioritize user security — and ProtonBrowser seems poised to lead the way. Are you ready for a privacy-first browser from Proton?</p><blockquote><a href="https://blog.moonsyntax.com/posts/proton-browser---a-privacy-focused-alternative-to-brave/">Read this Article on our website.</a></blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=5d3cf1d63e53" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/proton-browser-a-privacy-focused-alternative-to-brave-5d3cf1d63e53">Proton Browser — A Privacy-Focused Alternative to Brave?</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moon Syntax : Decoding Crypto Scams for You]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/moonsyntax/moon-syntax-decoding-crypto-scams-for-you-181474b3d730?source=rss----41a0eca91419---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/181474b3d730</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[trading]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Pryderi Cian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 15:32:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-09-29T21:03:11.895Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Moon Syntax : Decoding Crypto Scams for You</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fDoAOLiD4baMBGNr0hw5aA.png" /></figure><p>The crypto world can be a wild and unpredictable place, filled with opportunities and pitfalls. It’s a realm where moonshots can become a reality, but it’s also where scams and rug pulls lurk in the shadows. In this ever-changing landscape, you need a trustworthy guide, and that’s exactly what we offer.</p><h3>Who Are We?</h3><p>We are Moon syntax — a dedicated team of crypto enthusiasts and experts who’ve united under the Moon syntax banner. Our mission is to provide you with the knowledge and insights to navigate the crypto universe safely. With a majority of people perceiving crypto as a potential scam, we aim to debunk misconceptions by uncovering and exposing fraudulent projects. Our goal is to protect the reputation of legitimate ventures and foster trust within the crypto community, ensuring that the transformative potential of cryptocurrencies can be realized by all.</p><h3>Why Are We Doing This?</h3><p>The crypto space is like no other, with endless possibilities and risks that can catch even the most seasoned investors off guard. We’ve seen firsthand the damage scams can cause — not only to wallets but also to trust within the community. That’s why we’ve taken it upon ourselves to be the guardians of the Crypto galaxy.</p><p><strong>Our goal is simple: </strong>to offer you a reliable, free, and accessible resource. We conduct detailed project analyses, compiling all our research and findings for public access. We empower you to make well-informed decisions without the need for expensive crypto-analysis tools. We assess projects in detail, share our research, and provide ratings to help you avoid potential scams.</p><h3>What We Do:</h3><h4>Moon syntax Protection:</h4><p>Whether you’re an experienced trader, a VC or just dipping your toes into crypto, we’re your vigilant guardians. Have a crypto project in mind that you’re curious about? Request an analysis from our Moon syntax team, and we’ll investigate it for you.</p><h4>Daily Cosmic Investigations:</h4><p>In addition to user requests, we embark on daily missions to investigate random crypto projects. This ensures that we’re not just reacting to threats but actively seeking out potential scams in the vast crypto galaxy.</p><h4>Transparency:</h4><p>Our analyses are based on facts, research, and unbiased judgment. We leave no stone unturned when deciphering crypto projects, and our findings are presented transparently. Our reports reveal the mysteries of the projects we investigate, exposing potential red flags and areas of concern.</p><h4>Education and Empowerment:</h4><p>Our goal isn’t just to protect you from scams but also to empower you with knowledge. We want you to become a savvy crypto explorer who can make informed decisions independently.</p><h3>Community Constellation:</h3><p>We’re not just a team; we’re a constellation of crypto enthusiasts. We encourage active participation and cosmic discussions. Share your insights, questions, or concerns about a project with us and fellow stargazers.</p><p>In a universe where trust can be hard to find, Moon syntax is your celestial companion in the crypto space. Join us as we decode the secrets of crypto projects and safeguard the interests of the crypto community. Together, we can make the crypto world a safer, more transparent, and more thrilling place.</p><p>Welcome to Moon syntax — Your cosmic guides through the crypto cosmos.</p><blockquote><a href="https://blog.moonsyntax.com/posts/moon-syntax--decoding-crypto-scams-for-you/">Read this Article on our website.</a></blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=181474b3d730" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax/moon-syntax-decoding-crypto-scams-for-you-181474b3d730">Moon Syntax : Decoding Crypto Scams for You</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/moonsyntax">Moon Syntax</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>